Nobody wins solo
Eurovision Song Contest: The Story of Fire Saga is a
comedy, music film directed by David Dobkin.
Two small-town singers chase their pop star dreams at a global music competition,
where high stakes, scheming rivals and onstage mishaps test their bond.
Sigrit Ericksdottir, played by Rachel McAdams.
Lars Erickssong, played by Will Ferrell.
Erick Erickssong, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Alexander Lemtov, played by Dan Stevens.
Kevin Swain, played by Jamie Demetriou.
Neils Brongus, played by Ólafur Darri Ólafsson.
Eurovision Song Contest: The Story of Fire Saga is a 2020 American musical romantic comedy film directed by David Dobkin, written by Will Ferrell and Harper Steele, and starring
Ferrell, Rachel McAdams, Dan Stevens, Melissanthi Mahut, Mikael Persbrandt, Ólafur Darri Ólafsson, Graham Norton, Demi Lovato, Pierce Brosnan, and Elín Petersdóttir.
It follows the personally close Icelandic singers Lars Erickssong (Ferrell) and Sigrit Ericksdóttir
(McAdams) as they are given the chance to represent their country in the Eurovision Song Contest.
Development of a film based on the Eurovision Song Contest began in 2018, with Ferrell, a self-described
follower of the event, attending the 2018 and 2019 editions to conceive the characters and story.
The film was officially announced in June 2018, and filming took place
between August and October 2019 in Scotland, Iceland, and England.
The Story of Fire Saga was originally scheduled for a May 2020 release on
Netflix to coincide with the Eurovision Song Contest 2020.
Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the 2020 contest was canceled, and the
film was subsequently released a month later, on June 26.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the original
music but criticised the screenplay and runtime.
The film received a nomination for Best Original Song at
the 93rd Academy Awards (for "Husavik").
The film explores themes of pop star, competition,
rivalry, aspiring singer, singing competition.
The tone is lighthearted.